(Adapted from the web novel "Waiting for You in a City")
(Fireworks of My Heart)
(Episode 20)
Dr. Xu.
What a coincidence to run into you here.
What a coincidence.
It's quite a coincidence.
Are you out shopping too?
Yes. We're running out of daily necessities,
so we're replenishing them for everyone.
It's about time for us to return.
All right.
Mr. Song, it's fine for you to be strict...
with your subordinates.
But a doctor's personnel relationship...
stays in the hospital.
She's not an employee of the fire station.
The medical rescue team...
is working with you in joint hands.
Everyone is of equal status.
So...
forget about your rules...
that restrict personal freedom.
Let's be more humane.
Yan Chen.
I think...
Mr. Song won't ignore...
what I say, right?
Of course not.
Good advice...
should be taken into consideration.
Take your time shopping.
We'll get going.
Yan Chen, let's go.
Didn't I tell you...
to cut down on junk food?
Stay away from trash.
Yang Chi.
- Yes. - Do you want some?
- Yes. - Take it if you want some.
Are you waiting for me to feed you?
Let's go.
Dr. Xu.
Shopping time is over.
It's time to return to the team.
Yan Chen.
I have to go back to the fire station.
Isn't she on leave?
I'm sorry, Mr. Meng.
There's a time limit and regulations when we have outings.
I'll get going.
We'll give your suggestion...
a consideration.
- Back to work. - Yes.
(Automatic parking)
(Reverse parking)
Hello, Mom.
Give me a hint in the future for situations like this.
You gave me a scare.
You're just slow-witted.
Why didn't you discuss
about going to the fire station with the family?
Mom, this is work.
About what I said before,
did it go in one ear and out the other?
No.
Remember.
Come home this weekend.
The eldest son of the Dong family...
might come over for dinner.
- Mom, can I not... - No.
It's a done deal.
Good night.
Mom, I'm home.
Have you eaten?
Yes.
I came back to get something.
I'm going home after.
Wait.
Did you know...
that your sister...
went to the fire station?
Yes.
You did?
If you did,
why didn't you stop her?
Did she get together...
with Song Yan again?
No, they aren't together.
Meng Yan Chen,
you've gone too far.
You're lying to me.
Last time,
you paid the fine for them.
This time,
you hid the fact...
that she was at the fire station.
You're covering for her all the time.
It seems like...
I've given you two too much freedom...
and spoiled you.
All right. I'll get her another job...
at a high school or pharmaceutical company.
Mom.
Qin Qin likes being a doctor.
Let her stay in the hospital.
Mom.
Mr. Liu.
I don't think what you're doing is appropriate.
You're making young nurses and doctors...
stay at the fire station.
I know.
It's for work.
Of course I support you.
But I don't think this behavior...
is appropriate.
Of course we have to meet.
Yes, we must.
We're in the transition phase.
If we encounter any problems,
we'll correct them in time.
Yes.
Thank you, Mr. Liu.
What's the matter?
We received a complaint from the family of a medical personnel.
They want them to move out of the fire station.
But they're supposed to dispatch with us.
However, it's true.
They work 24 hours a day...
and don't know when they'll be dispatched.
It's understandable.
What do you think?
Their demand is reasonable.
It's fine for them move to out.
It's already a miracle that they agreed...
to be dispatched together.
The doctors...
aren't firefighters after all.
They have their own lives too.
There are only a few of them.
Who could have complained?
Could it be Xu Qin's mom?
She seems like a ruthless woman.
Hello.
I was thinking...
it's about time you came to see me.
Is this how you were raised?
Regarding our feud,
you...
still care about the silly name-calling?
Yes.
It was me.
I know.
Apart from you,
no one would have done that.
I thought you would come to me.
Actually, I did want to see you.
It's nothing much.
I was just curious about what kind of person you are.
But come to think of it,
you've probably been waiting to see me.
So why not let you wait a little longer?
You've matured.
Thank you.
I've been through a lot.
Of course I've matured.
Back then, if you were so composed...
in front of your dad's grave,
I guess...
I wouldn't have been able to do anything to you.
You can't...
do anything to me now either.
Is that so?
If I wanted to,
it would be a piece of cake for me.
I beg you!
Please let my son go!
- You can't ruin him like this! - Get him out of here.
I beg you, please let my child go.
You can't ruin his future!
Get him out of here.
I'm begging you.
Let my son go, I'm begging you!
You can't ruin his future like this!
- I'm begging you! - Hey, leave!
I'm begging you!
Let my son go!
You can't ruin his future like this!
I'm begging you!
Please!
You can't ruin my child's future like this!
Excuse me, here's your coffee.
Don't mess with my family again.
This isn't ten years ago.
I'm not that kid from before either.
If you really want to fight,
I'll skin you alive.
That won't be a problem for me.
My dad was hard to deal with, wasn't he?
And I'm tougher than him.
All right.
You and Qin Qin...
should stop seeing each other.
Are you that afraid of me?
I'm not.
You're just not worthy.
Song Yan.
Actually,
I used to admire your dad.
He was an honest man.
But he was too rigid...
and careless in making friends.
And you...
Don't you have any self-respect?
There's such a huge gap...
between our families,
yet you still like Qin Qin.
I wonder...
if you have other intentions.
Or...
if you are just like...
your mom.
We have different values.
There's nothing for us to talk about.
To you,
people are divided into ranks.
To me,
everyone is equal.
In my life,
I've never pandered to anyone...
nor looked down on anyone.
But I look down on you.
What a shame.
Come on, stand up.
Move forward.
Hold it further.
Hold it.
Stop.
Mr. Yang.
We haven't tried the water gun.
Can we have a go?
I don't think so.
You girls aren't strong enough.
The water gun is quite strong.
No, we...
We're strong too.
Just let us try.
We're leaving soon.
Well...
Okay. I'll let you try it.
Take a break.
- Okay. - Take off two sets of uniforms.
- Come with me. - Okay.
Ms. Nan.
- Dr. Xu, take a video for me. - Here.
Okay.
Hold it.
One leg in front.
- One leg in front. Got it? - Okay.
Bend your waist a bit.
You must clamp it. It's really strong.
Okay.
- Turn on the water. - Okay.
Not too much pressure.
Wait. Hold it.
- Pull it back and it'll turn on. - Okay.
- Are you ready? - Ready!
Turn on the water.
- I... - I'm turning it on, Dong Dong.
Three, two, one.
Are you okay?
Are you okay, Dr. Xu?
Dr. Xu, are you okay?
You two, be careful.
Take a look.
Here.
Put on your clothes before coming out.
Hairdryer.
Dry your hair. Don't catch a cold.
Dr. Xu, you're a doctor.
How could you be so clumsy?
That's strange.
Your sleeves are too long and fat.
It makes it difficult.
Sit down.
You're getting my hair tangled.
Do you still need my help?
Why are you laughing?
You look like a ghost.
You're the one who turned me into a ghost.
(Wood Workshop)
Here.
Don't catch a cold.
Take a hot shower.
Uncle and Aunt are here.
What if they come in in the middle of the shower?
I'll get caught.
All right, take a shower.
I'll wait for you outside.
Song Yan.
Where's the hairdryer?
How long have you been a firefighter?
A long time.
That means...
you were in the military.
Of course.
Back then, you said...
you wanted to go to military school.
I failed my college entrance exam the second time.
Don't think too much.
It has nothing to do with you leaving.
I was never good at studying.
But I remember when you repeated the exam,
you improved a lot.
You're mistaken.
All right. It's about dry.
Why do I feel like...
you're not telling me the truth?
Song Yan.
What truth?
I want to know everything about you...
after we broke up.
Can't you tell me?
No, I can't.
Why not?
It's my own business.
It has nothing to do with you.
Nothing to do with me?
Are you being serious?
Then why did I come to the fire station this time?
If that's the case,
you shouldn't have come.
You didn't want me to come?
It has nothing to do with that either.
Then what does it have to do with?
We've missed ten years together.
I want to fill that ten-year gap.
What for, Xu Qin?
A missed time is a missed time.
You can't make up for it...
just because you want to.
Why are you clinging to the past...
and not letting it go?
You said it.
We need time...
to get to know each other.
To understand each other once again.
To see if the person in front of us...
will make our hearts flutter.
If we will like each other.
If we want to be with each other once again.
But the person in front of me...
also came to me after going through the past.
I want to know...
what you have been through for the past ten years.
I want to know about your past.
What's wrong with that?
You can find out.
But Dr. Xu,
right now,
what are we?
Are we friends?
Or lovers?
What kind of identity will you use...
to find out about my past?
Song Yan.
Are you drawing a line between us?
Are you trying to say...
that I've crossed the line...
if we're friends?
I don't know.
I don't know what went wrong with us.
How did we end up at this dead end?
Dead end?
Maybe we shouldn't see each other so often.
If we don't see each other,
we'll keep our distance.
That's good.
You're right.
We should keep our distance.
It's my wishful thinking.
It's all my problem.
I'm sorry.
It'll be over after today.
From now on,
we'll have fewer chances to see each other.
Everything will be okay.
You mean...
You mean after today,
we'll never see each other again?
I see.
So that's what you meant...
when you gave me that gift.
Thank you.
I wish you all the best,
Mr. Song.
Dr. Xu, you just got drenched.
Drink some hot water.
What if you really get sick tomorrow?
It's hot.
- Be careful. - Did you make this?
Drink some.
I have to take care of you on everyone's behalf.
Thank you.
Can I go back to the hospital first?
No way.
You're the team leader.
It's ridiculous if you don't show up.
Drink up.
We have to be there.
I was wondering where you were.
Let's go to the farewell dinner.
What farewell dinner?
Dr. Xu and the others are all there.
They're having a farewell dinner with us.
I have an upset stomach.
Don't be like that. We're waiting for you.
How can you not show up? Let's go.
Hurry up. Come on.
Let's go.
Comrades, let me propose a toast.
We should make a toast...
to the medical staff.
Thank you for your hard work.
Cheers.
- Thank you for your hard work. - Thank you for your hard work.
Well, as the medical team,
we should thank you for taking care of us.
Thank you all.
Don't mention it.
We're on the same team.
We're a family from now on.
- Yes. - Come often.
Ms. Nan, you too.
Sure, we'll come here often.
I'll definitely come often.
I'll bring my son here.
What?
Ms. Bei, you have a son?
- No. - You look so young,
as if you just graduated from medical school.
No, he's my godson.
Well, you still look young.
Ms. Nan, do you have a son?
Pi Pi, you don't have to worry about that.
Dr. Li is so fair.
I'm sure she has many suitors.
I think so too.
Don't be nosy.
I don't.
During every holiday,
my mom arranges blind dates for me.
Forget about me.
You guys aren't worried about this matter, right?
Don't people say...
the most handsome men belong to the country?
Actually, it's strange.
In our station,
those who have a partner are the quiet ones.
Like Jiang Yi,
Ge Zheng,
Yuan Hai, and Kai Liu.
They're all quite quiet.
Right, Ge Zheng?
But you're still so talkative.
If you put it that way,
Chief is the least talkative.
Do you have a girlfriend too?
Don't you know, Dong Dong?
He's madly in love.
He has been waiting for his first love for ten years.
Is that so?
I heard it from Jiang Yi.
Just say it if you want to.
Why did you sell me out?
Chief, you're so romantic.
So there are...
such romantic people in the world.
Tell us, Chief.
Come on.
Jiang Yi was just talking nonsense.
That's not true.
Dig in.
Chief.
What's there to be shy about?
All of us know it.
That's right.
Well, I'll prove it for Jiang Yi.
What Jiang Yi said...
is all true.
All right, stop gossiping.
So where's the girl?
I don't know.
She's abroad.
Does she know you've always liked her...
and been waiting for her?
It doesn't matter if she knows or not.
We won't be together anyway.
So many years have passed.
People change.
Some relationships...
don't have to be forced.
As long as there are memories...
and they're doing well,
that's the best ending.
It's such a shame.
That's right, Chief.
Don't you regret it?
It's life.
How can there be no regrets?
That's right.
I have regrets too.
For example, this joint rescue team...
didn't achieve the goal I expected.
I'm a little disappointed.
How come?
We've learned a lot here.
That's right.
We gained a lot of knowledge.
If we hadn't come,
we wouldn't know that firefighters have to do so much.
That's because the system has changed.
Look.
Fires,
emergency rescue,
social assistance,
and total disaster response...
are now all under our jurisdiction.
Anyway, all I know is after the system has changed,
we are a paramilitary force.
We spend more time on missions.
Yes, and the benefits...
are much better than before.
If it can be improved in the future,
that would be even better.
What benefits?
We're serving the people.
Yes, we're serving the people.
- Yes. - Yes.
Indeed.
No reward is too much...
for what you do.
Restructuring is a great thing.
Yes.
We're more specialized, detailed, and professional.
All of us who are involved...
think it's a good thing.
I hope...
our working environment and system can change too.
Actually, I think...
your job is quite tough too.
Yes.
Compared to yours,
yours is tougher.
Actually,
I really don't like words like heroism,
sentiment,
dedication, and sacrifice.
Words like that...
shouldn't be associated with a particular profession.
A job should be a job itself.
What do you mean?
In society,
no job should be the generator of love.
The public shouldn't ask...
any group of people to devote themselves.
A job is a job.
It can have responsibilities and a mission.
But at its core, it's just a job.
There's no need...
to put a halo on it.
We're all ordinary people.
How much value you create...
is how much you should be rewarded.
Other than that,
don't give your job too much...
other than what it is.
Especially the grand philosophy...
and the grand halo.
Are you denying the halo of our profession?
I just think that things shouldn't be like that.
Like what?
Forget it. You won't understand.
Eat up. Come on.
Do you think...
we're all living in a false dream of heroism?
Actually,
I think this...
Dr. Xu.
Come out for a second.
Chief.
- Dr. Xu. - Dr. Xu...
Why don't I go and check on them?
Sit.
There are so many dishes. Don't waste them.
Don't be nosy.
Let's eat.
Do you think...
those people in there,
your colleagues,
my buddies,
are fools...
who are self-hypnotized by these false dreams of heroism...
all day long?
That's why we chose this profession...
and persisted until now?
You know that's not what I meant.
I know what you meant.
You've always been smart.
You're so smart that everyone is a fool in your eyes.
Including me.
Why are you mad at me?
What I said wasn't wrong.
Indeed.
What you said is very in character of you.
Really.
Xu Qin.
You're still the same as before.
You don't owe anyone anything.
And you won't allow anyone to take anything away from you.
Can't I be objective?
What kind of objective?
There are many kinds of work in this society.
Every profession has its own challenges.
Everyone in their jobs...
has their own difficulties.
Sanitation workers don't have it easy.
Teachers don't have it easy.
Police officers don't have it easy.
Those who guard the borders don't have it easy.
But some special jobs...
that involve public works...
and social care...
are not something
that can be explained with money.
When a profession becomes better...
and improves,
it's because of the effort...
and action of everyone in it.
Not just words.
We face so many things every day.
Matters and feelings.
Xu Qin.
You only see things.
You don't feel.
Do you love your job?
Do you only love your job?
I do.
It's not just me.
So do Jiang Yu,
Yang Chi, and Jiang Yi.
I believe so do Li Nan and Xu Xi.
To you,
it's silly, right?
Do you know?
The words "I am willing"...
can't be bought even with money.
But there are some people...
who are like fools.
They see things...
with their feelings.
(Dare to face dangerous situations, dare to brave the sea of fire)
They're willing to be angels.
They're willing to be heroes.
They're willing to sacrifice themselves for nothing else.
You have no right to look down on them.
I'm not looking down on anyone.
I just want to tell you rationally...
Your rationale is superior...
and cruel.
What you did today...
was highly inappropriate.
Goodbye,
Dr. Xu.
Song Yan.
You misunderstood me.
I just don't want to see you guys...
take such risks for your beliefs.
I don't want your profession...
to be a burden on you.
(Yan City Firefighter)
(Yan City Firefighter, Yanbei Division)
Yang Chi.
Where's the gift you brought for Ms. Xu Xi?
- I know. - Where is it?
Shut up.
Ms. Xu Xi.
This is for you. I know you love it.
So I bought it for you.
Tell me when you run out.
- I'll buy you more. - I don't have a gift for you.
I wish you all the best at work.
Okay.
- Remember to do your laundry. - I will.
- Okay, we'll get going. - Bye.
- Okay. - Instructor.
- Bye. - Do me a favor.
- What is it, Dr. Xu? - Come back often.
About what happened just now,
please apologize to everyone on my behalf.
Sometimes, I don't find the right words to say.
I really didn't mean it.
I know.
The two of you were talking in a rush.
Talked too fast.
Don't take it to heart.
Dr. Xu, don't think too much.
We all know that you didn't mean it.
I know you feel bad for us.
We've known each other for so long.
How can we not know what kind of person you are?
Chief might not be in a good mood today.
Don't take it to heart.
Goodbye.
Take care.
- You don't want to leave? - Don't want to go?
You want to stay?
- Bye. - Bye.